<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>STRUCK ME LIKE A CHORD</title>
    <link href="https://struckmelikeachord.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://struckmelikeachord.com" />
    <updated>2026-02-01T18:08:56-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Benji</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://struckmelikeachord.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>IN CONVERSATION WITH TOM O&#x27;DONNELL</title>
        <author>
            <name>Benji</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://struckmelikeachord.com/in-conversation-with-tom-odonnell.html"/>
        <id>https://struckmelikeachord.com/in-conversation-with-tom-odonnell.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/tom3.jpeg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2026-01-14T17:25:16-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/tom3.jpeg" alt="" />
                    IN CONVERSATION WITH TOM O'DONNELL Interview and photography by Benji Wason After&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/tom3.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                
    <h2 id="in-conversation-with-tom-odonnell" class="align-center">
      IN CONVERSATION WITH TOM O'DONNELL
    </h2>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/tom3-2.jpeg" height="2060" width="2342" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/tom3-2-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/tom3-2-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/tom3-2-md.jpeg 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/tom3-2-lg.jpeg 1024w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    Interview and photography by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/benji_wason/">Benji Wason</a>
  </p>

  <p>
    After finishing our interview, Tom O’Donnell proceeds to do what he always does when we hang out - he shows me a new demo. As the jarring drum rhythm starts to pump through a blown out bluetooth speaker, he nods his head to the beat.  “It was one of the first ones in forever where I’m like ‘I’m the guitar player in a band, and I just wrote a <em>sick riff</em>.’” <br><br>As he describes in infectious detail how the idea emerged at a rehearsal jam with his band <a href="https://www.instagram.com/samevein.nyc/" target="_blank">Same Vein</a>, I point out that it’s no wonder he’s always coming up with ideas — while most guitarists have to consciously try to practice and develop their musicality, he constantly has to learn new material from whoever recruited him for a gig that weekend, his sets with both <a href="https://www.instagram.com/lavedamusic/">Laveda</a> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/knotted_____/">Knotted</a> on New Year’s Eve being a recent example. “I’ve been very lucky in that respect,” he says, “I’ve almost always had to learn some shit because I had a deadline in five days and that was it.”
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/IMG_8806.JPG" height="4492" width="6774" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8806-xs.JPG 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8806-sm.JPG 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8806-md.JPG 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8806-lg.JPG 1024w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    Since arriving in New York in early 2021 O’Donnell has had plenty of dates and deadlines to fill his calendar — from finishing the mixes for Same Vein’s <em><a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/2JkTmruklfWshCqmd0mcq9">Old Small World</a></em> in one month, to gigs with <a href="https://www.instagram.com/thedownandoutsmusic/">The Down &amp; Outs</a>, tours with <a href="https://www.instagram.com/couchprints/">Couch Prints</a>, and being phoned in as the emergency drummer for <a href="https://www.instagram.com/monobloc.online/">Monobloc</a> one week before their Gov Ball debut. <br><br>But these are in a way incidental to his musical path, because between all the gigs and studio sessions, O’Donnell is never <em>not</em> working on, playing, or talking about music. And it’s this devotion and authentic commitment to craft that has made him a sought after collaborator, player, and producer, as well as a close friend of many in the local scene, myself included.<br><br>For Struck Me Like A Chord’s latest feature, I talk to Tom about cutting his teeth at Boston jam sessions, stumbling into opportunities in New York City bars, and doing everything in service of the song with his new project Same Vein. Read the full interview below.<br>
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/tom4-3.png" height="640" width="424" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/tom4-3-xs.png 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/tom4-3-sm.png 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/tom4-3-md.png 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/tom4-3-lg.png 1024w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    <strong>I want to start with your current, most recent focus, which is Same Vein. Could you tell me basically how that came about, how you met B and where that all started?<br></strong><br>So I met B at Mona's on 13th and B. They had jazz nights on Tuesdays, and she kind of picked me out of the crowd — I think her line was, “I have a tab open and there's a minimum, can I buy you a drink so I can close out?” <br><br>We had a drink and shot the shit for a little while, and then she was like, “Oh, hold on, I have to go sit in now,”  and I wasn’t sure what she meant, but then she just got on stage and did “Dream a Little Dream of Me”, looking at me the whole time. It was piercing, incredible.
  </p>

  <p>
    We chatted a bit about maybe making music down the line, but then I ran into her again the next day on the L train at the 14th and 1st stop, because we had both left our cards open at Mona's the night before. It was just like “Ok, this needs to happen.” <br>
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/IMG_8818.JPG" height="4492" width="6774" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8818-xs.JPG 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8818-sm.JPG 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8818-md.JPG 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8818-lg.JPG 1024w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    When we started playing together we had a residency in the East Village where we were doing jazz standards and some originals that didn't fit any of my other projects. And pretty quickly, she was writing some incredible stuff just off of little ideas that we'd be improvising. So that came together pretty naturally over the course of six months.<br><br><strong>Was the sound of Same Vein something that you had an idea of before it even came together, or do you feel like it mostly emerged from the chemistry of the group?<br></strong><br>When me and B started working together, I think I had ideas that I didn't know if I could deliver right, and I was just really excited to see what she would do with them. And I had a bit of a stylistic tilt towards exploring gothy, jazzy stuff that we had in common anyway. <br><br>When Esme (Rumblehart, violin) joined it certainly brought out a little more of the country and noir-y, cinematic elements. But I mean, we had half a record written by the time we even considered what the band would be. I think pretty immediately  my vision of what it would be got pushed in the background, because we  were just coming up with shit at such an incredible clip.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/IMG_7197.JPG" height="4492" width="6774" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_7197-xs.JPG 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_7197-sm.JPG 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_7197-md.JPG 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_7197-lg.JPG 1024w">
      <figcaption>B</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    We didn't really have to spend a lot of time thinking about cohesion or stylistic representation in any particular way. It was just cooking, constantly. And then it got to a point where it was like, well, these were all recorded the same way. These were all done in the apartment. These were all done on this microphone, within a two month period of each other. And those were really just the ones that got finished in like a night. <br><br>Almost everything else —  if it took more than three days, it got stuck in a folder somewhere. But those four songs were pretty much done the night that we recorded them. You'd wake up the next morning and go, “We can send it to mastering, like now.” <br><br>It was also very collaborative. We were really lucky to have a lot of cool people in the room while shit was getting written, and some of the most important parts on the record are not played by anybody who's “in the band.” So a lot of the sound of the EP was just dictated by who happened to be in the house at the time.<br><br><strong>Taking a step back, how did you get into music? What was the first instrument you learned, or the artists that really turned you on?<br></strong><br>I started playing guitar kind of casually, before I really knew what I liked. But I think when I moved back to the east coast at 11 years old, I very quickly just felt like everything that I had listened to when I was a kid living in California for a couple of years was just bad. I was just like, “Alright, so blink 182 sucks.”  Then I got into a lot of the old pre-punk stuff, The Stooges and The Velvet Underground and that sort of thing. And that just broke the doors down. <br><br>I found a bootleg of the Don Lets documentary Punk Attitude. It's in chronological order, and I remember watching it in pieces because it was on Vimeo or something. And literally overnight I went from being like, “I don't really know what I like,” to being like, “The New York Dolls and The Stooges and The Velvet Underground are the coolest thing ever, and I'm in love with this.”
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/IMG_8803.JPG" height="4492" width="6774" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8803-xs.JPG 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8803-sm.JPG 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8803-md.JPG 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8803-lg.JPG 1024w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    Years later, I eventually found out that a lot of the stuff that I listened to as a kid was really fucking dope. My old man was just playing like Motown and Little Richard and stuff like that around the house a lot. It wasn't until I did the punk circle, and then went back to some of the older stuff that it was drawing from, that I kind of realized that I knew all these songs already. <br><br><strong>Was there a band that you were in early on?<br></strong><br>In high school I did a lot of recording at my old man and stepmother's place. They were pretty cool with me just being loud, which I was really grateful for. And my old man's a musician, so there was a little bit of gear around the house to toy around with. <br><br>I spent some years learning how to use GarageBand and shitty Tascam tape machines and stuff. And then tried to put a band together in high school, which was whatever buddy you could, you know…<br><br><strong>Bribe.<br></strong><br>Exactly. “I'll bring the weed if you can play bass.” And some of the cats that I ended up playing with after some time were really brilliant players, and I got to be like the young guitar player and cut my teeth doing that sort of thing. But nothing lasted very long.<br><br>My buddy Gil, who was in a band called <a href="https://soundcloud.com/artyslang">Arty $lang</a>, hosted a music night in Lowell called Music Mondays. It was upstairs from the club that everybody played and was like the only all ages venue in town. So before I was 21 everybody was playing there.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/260127001121580021.jpg" height="2075" width="3130" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/260127001121580021-xs.jpg 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/260127001121580021-sm.jpg 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/260127001121580021-md.jpg 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/260127001121580021-lg.jpg 1024w">
      <figcaption>Performing with Laveda on New Year's Eve</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    Music Mondays was weird because it was like pro jazz guys and funk guys and, you know, old heads — and then, like, dumb ass, acid fried fucking, can-barely-play-their-instrument musicians. Like 12 people playing at the same time. It was ridiculous. And the jam wouldn't end, the drummer would just get tired and hand the sticks to somebody else. So I kind of learned how to play drums and keyboards doing that, because I was a decent guitar player, and I knew I could fill in all these other blanks. If there's eight fucking guitar players I don't need to be sitting in, you know? It was cool also to be exposed to that sort of stuff where you're playing with people who are way out of your league, but are also glad to be shooting the shit with you. That was definitely formative. <br><br>And then from there I was in bands, touring pretty young. I didn't go to college or anything like that, so that was kind of my whole life, pretty much immediately out of high school. Which has never really stopped, and eventually I landed here.<br><br><strong>You’re constantly collaborating with different musicians and working on a lot of projects. What was your story as far as making it down to New York and constellating all of that after you got here?<br></strong><br>I lucked out and stumbled into a lot of shit, just right time, right place I guess. My band in Boston, and the label that I was running when covid hit — everything just collapsed. Our tours fell to pieces, the album rollout died in the water, the label collapsed, all those bands broke up, we ran out of money. Just everything fucking collapsed.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/tom5.jpeg" height="2161" width="2069" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/tom5-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/tom5-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/tom5-md.jpeg 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/tom5-lg.jpeg 1024w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    And so I moved to New York. I knew some rappers that we had played with in New York that I had done a little bit of production stuff with. So I kind of thought that my focus when I got down here might be doing more production work. <br><br>Then I stumbled into Ray (Young, of The Down &amp; Outs) at the Johnsons and the <a href="https://www.instagram.com/beenstellar/">Been Stellar</a> guys one night. I ended up filling in on drums with you guys, and meeting Brandon (Tong, of Couch Prints) through Rubulad. I met a lot of people through you guys, doing the work on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/traderockstar/">Deuén</a>’s record, filling in with Monobloc, eventually meeting <a href="https://www.instagram.com/jimilucid/">Jimi Lucid</a> — all of those things stemmed from just like, stumbling into people at bars. <br><br>Ray was a big dot connector for me, he seemed to really enjoy shoving me into a room and just being like, “They'll love you!” Next thing you knew, I just had gigs everywhere filling in for all kinds of people, and a lot of them ended up being really close friends.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/IMG_8799.JPG" height="4492" width="6774" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8799-xs.JPG 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8799-sm.JPG 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8799-md.JPG 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8799-lg.JPG 1024w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    After working with The Down &amp; Outs and the initial couple tours with Couch Prints, and a lot of the session work here and there, I tried the Temprec thing, which lasted three months or something. <br><br><strong>One of my favorite bands of all time.<br></strong><br>The issue was, everybody in the band was in a band, you know? It just wasn't sustainable. And there was, like, a weird, maybe dead period month where we kind of killed that project, and I really just didn't know what was going to happen next. I met B in that same period that I had this back catalog of songs, and I didn't really have a band. The timing just landed pretty well where I kind of had a focus again.<br><br><strong>What has come out this year that you were a part of? It doesn't have to be every single thing but what were a couple highlights?<br></strong><br>Well, ”<a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/7gldtlEbcSESQpg2bA8U5P?si=345bde47bb704eb7">TRUST ME</a>” just came out and I have to say, it's been one of my favorite songs that we've had — I always just thought it was the best chorus that Ray ever wrote. <br>It's also, of that EP, I thought that was my best production work. I thought that was the one that was most simultaneously true to the demo, but also the studio shit was like, “Oh, thank God we did this studio session.” That one, I'm really genuinely proud of. I’m so fucking glad that it’s finally seeing the light of day.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/260127001121580004.jpg" height="2075" width="3130" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/260127001121580004-xs.jpg 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/260127001121580004-sm.jpg 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/260127001121580004-md.jpg 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/260127001121580004-lg.jpg 1024w">
      <figcaption>With The Down & Outs (photo by Ben Scofield)</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    There’s also the Couch Prints <a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/2ggSCc2DysnnwlYk6Arr6V?si=KSPVT47ySFKwX0riMGFUbQ">album</a>. That record went through so many variations — there were like 12 versions of that record where none of the songs sound even remotely similar to what they eventually sounded like. It wasn't until it was actually released, that I listened to it on headphones on the train and heard it start to finish effectively when everybody else did. I love the closer on that record, “Laughter.” That one I'm also very proud of.<br><br><strong>Are there a few pieces of gear that you find indispensable?<br></strong><br>I mean, there's some dumb, obvious ones that I just swear by. I think the Big Muff is the greatest guitar pedal ever invented. If there was ever a thing that was designed to do a task, that did the fucking task…it's a perfect pedal. <br><br>Then there’s the line six delay. I've never used it on my pedal board, but I've used it for production stuff and used it for outboard  synthesizer effects. That thing is phenomenal, great for overdubbing. <br><br>The Kaos Pad too is great for just getting off the grid, when you need to stop thinking rationally, you know? They call it chaos pad for a reason, I guess. It's very much like, throw it into a blender and just see what comes out. <br><br>Also this probably should be on record, because it’s actually quite important: the Electro-Voice RE20. Almost everything on the EP is recorded on that mic — all the violins, all the vocals, all the guitars. That microphone is the whole record. And I think the reason that the record sounds the way that it sounds is because that thing is just capturing the room. That thing has been essential.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/260127001121580015.jpg" height="2075" width="3130" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/260127001121580015-xs.jpg 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/260127001121580015-sm.jpg 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/260127001121580015-md.jpg 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/260127001121580015-lg.jpg 1024w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    <strong>Last question: how do you want your musicianship to evolve in the future?<br></strong><br>I think nowadays I'm more concerned with the song. Everything now is in service to that. I used to be, as a producer, maybe more concerned with ear-candy and referential sound design-y sort of stuff. And as a guitar player, maybe I was in my head about trying to incorporate stuff that wasn't, you know, the obvious rock influence.<br><br>Part of the benefit of working with so many different people has been recognizing what everybody else in the room's strengths are and trying to make sure that those things get heard. The most fun part about doing the Same Vein stuff is not what I might even bring to it. I'm just facilitating other people's best ideas and getting the best take out of them.<br><br>I want to be on point and all that, but I'm not very concerned with becoming a better guitar player right now. I've got better guitar players in my apartment every day who can do shit that I wouldn't dream of doing. My job nowadays is to make sure that the fucking mic is rolling when they start doing that.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/IMG_8800.JPG" height="4492" width="6774" alt=""  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8800-xs.JPG 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8800-sm.JPG 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8800-md.JPG 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/10/responsive/IMG_8800-lg.JPG 1024w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>IN CONVERSATION WITH COMET</title>
        <author>
            <name>Benji</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://struckmelikeachord.com/in-conversation-with-comet.html"/>
        <id>https://struckmelikeachord.com/in-conversation-with-comet.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/9/dblack-2023-09-21-081728.JPEG" medium="image" />

        <updated>2025-11-12T20:53:33-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/9/dblack-2023-09-21-081728.JPEG" alt="" />
                    When I ask Comet when she first became interested in having a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/9/dblack-2023-09-21-081728.JPEG" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I ask Comet when she first became interested in having a career in music, the NYC-based songwriter says that the desire started early, but took some time to accept. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I have honestly always wanted to do that,” she says, “But when I was a kid, my mom was always like, “Oh, you can't be a musician, that makes no money,” like “You shouldn’t even try.” So for years, I remember I would tell kids on the playground —  they'd be like, “I want to be a pop star,” and I’d be like, “There’s no money in that.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Luckily for us, she eventually changed her mind.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“As I got older I realized that's not really true,” she says, “I definitely have plenty of friends where all they do is make music, and that's how they survive. And so, it's showing that it's possible. And, I don't know, but I always wanted to be a rock star, ever since I was a kid. But doesn't everyone kind of?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I caught up with Comet earlier this year to chat about her upcoming music projects, darker art making a comeback, lost innocence, the music scene in NYC vs LA, and more.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>When I saw you perform at ONOS, I noticed a lot of the music and the tone is dark and can be really heavy, but you totally balance it with tight songcraft and arrangements, which makes it pack so much more of a punch in my opinion.</strong></p>
<p><strong>I'm curious if you have different influences that relate to those aspects of your style, or if there's 1 or 2 artists that were really essential for you in finding your sound?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I feel like my main influences are very classic — Courtney Love, The Distillers, and just girl rock in general. But I love this kind of revival of that Def Tones-y kind of sound. I really like Sunn O))), and bands that are heavy and kind of gazy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I wouldn't say my stuff is very Shoe Gaze-y, but I do think that there are some fuzzy elements in it. I like vocals a lot, that's what I think is actually my strong suit. I'm not that great of a guitar player.</span></p>
<p><strong>Yeah, when I saw you perform I noticed you had a really great control of your voice. You also did this kind of scream-singing thing — I don't know what you call that, but I thought it was an impressive, skillful way of really pushing your voice. Did you take lessons, did you train, or did you just teach yourself?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I come from a musical family. My dad was an opera singer and a ballet dancer, and when I was really young he put both me and my sister into dance lessons and voice lessons and whatever. I even took piano for a while, but I never really was good at an instrument. I was very impatient with instruments. But I've always loved singing, I would sing in the car as a kid and stuff. I didn't take voice lessons for a long time as an adult but I feel like a lot of it is natural and just practice over the years.</span></p>
<p><strong>So having that initial training, in the long run, you kind of have those fundamentals to build upon when you get into other things that they probably weren't showing you, with heavier music and stuff.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For sure. As far as screaming goes, I literally just did it until it sounded not cringey anymore, because I feel like screaming can sound so cringey.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><strong>So, correct me if I'm wrong, but you grew up in LA?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I grew up in Florida mostly. I was born in London, and I grew up in Florida for most of my young life. And then when I was 17, I moved to LA.</span></p>
<p><strong>And is that where you started to perform more and kind of try to create an artistic identity?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah. I’d written like lyrics and stuff when I was younger, but I never really performed or had a band or anything until I was 18, almost 19. I dropped out of college and just decided to form one. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I picked up a guitar for the first time when I was like 18. It was senior year of high school. One of my friends, we would always go to her house and make songs and stuff. And she was like, “Oh, do you want to play the guitar for this one?” and I said, “Oh, I don't know how to play the guitar,” and she was like, “Me neither.” And I was like, “Oh. Well, I guess you can just kind of fuck around.” Then I had a band in LA, and we made an album when I was like 19. And that first album, I literally did not know how to play guitar. Like, we decided to make an album, and I could not even tell you like a single chord on the guitar. I just was like, “Let's do it.” </span></p>
<p><strong>And was that as Comet, or as a different band?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was my first band. We were called Girl Theme. We still have put out some stuff, recently. But I feel like right now, I am newly focusing on Comet since I've moved.</span></p>
<p><strong>Right. So, what was that move like and what has the direction been with Comet as a project since then?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It's been great. I'm so happy that I moved, I feel like the scene here is a lot better. I feel like there's a lot more young people making interesting music. LA is just like a bunch of rock...well, for one it’s a bunch of dudes, but also it's a bunch of 30-year-old dudes that, for the most part, are doing cover songs, or making a song about a girl named Sarah. And, I don't know, it's not interesting at all. And here, I feel like there's a lot more people my age like making interesting music of all kinds. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Direction wise, I released an EP last summer that was completely just done by myself. I recorded every instrument. I programmed the drums, or got a studio drummer to do them, and I mixed and mastered it and put it out myself.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But since coming here, I've been working with my bassist, Grant Lepping. And we are recording in the studio that he works at. It's going to be my first studio project, this EP that we're working on right now.</span></p>
<p><strong>With that self-produced project, was that something that you just totally undertook to learn through like YouTube tutorials or asking friends in terms of mixing and mastering and stuff like that?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Honestly, I can't watch YouTube tutorials. It doesn't make sense to me. I can't like learn that way.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My band's projects were all produced by other people, and so I just watched them. And then the rest has kind of just been trial and error. But I feel like watching someone produce my band’s projects, I was like, “Oh, I could do this.” They would be doing stuff sometimes, and I’m thinking, “If I was doing it, I would do it like this.”</span></p>
<p><strong>You said you were taking your time right now recording a proper studio album, what are you drawing from in this moment — inspiration wise, vibe wise, from life experiences, etc.?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I feel like mostly, I'm drawing from the really awful state of the world, and the constant darkness that it is to be a woman. That is... those are my main inspirations right now. And lost innocence. I feel like lost innocence sums up the EP for the most part.</span></p>
<p><strong>As a central theme in the writing that you do overall?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, definitely. And just accepting the way things are.</span></p>
<p><strong>I was digging into the rest of your catalog after seeing your perform, and I was really captivated by the lyric writing. You said you'd always kind of played with writing songs, has writing in general been something that you've connected with for a long time? And were there any writers or authors that inspired you tonally or through their style?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I love Sylvia Plath and VC Andrews. I feel like writing is like the only thing I'm actually good at. I feel like I could go up to someone else who's good at writing lyrics and still say I'm good at writing lyrics. But guitar, no. To someone who's a classically trained singer, I wouldn’t go up to them and be like, “I'm a good singer.” But I would go up to a good lyricist and be like, “I'm a good lyricist.”</span></p>
<p><strong>What current art is inspiring you right now? You talked about the kind of community and the scene that we have going around here — are there people or projects or artists that are making things that you're really into at the moment?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, I love Richard Orth. He's so great. He's my friend. We made a song together for the EP that we have coming out. I've never worked with someone who produces music that I feel like they make it sound exactly how I wanted to without me having to tell them. But he is really good. And then I love this band in LA that I played a show with called Faetooth. They're like a doom metal all-girl band.</span></p>
<p><strong>Is there some part of your work that you're looking to dive deeper into, express more totally or just refine with the new recordings?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I want this EP to be technically good. I love a lot of my songwriting, a lot of like the old songs even that I've released that were recorded so horribly. I still like how they sound, but I’m like, “If this was recorded better, people would connect with it more.” And so this time, I really want to focus on the technical aspects of recording it well, getting tones right, mixing it properly. Yeah, I guess the technical aspect. Because I feel like everything else is there. </span></p>
<p><strong>Yeah it sounds like a way to sort of round out the project intention by making it just more artfully presented and crafted.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah. I want to take my time. Like, no one knows who I am. There's no reason for me to rush.</span></p>
<p><strong>Do you think of yourself right now as really just focusing on the art that, once presented to the world, you’ll be able to build off of as a strong foundation?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Definitely. I mean, I do have a release schedule, blah, blah blah. I don't have dates but I have ideas of how I want to do it. But as far as rushing and putting out random singles and stuff, I don't really care to do that. I actually hate the single world we live in, I feel like it's so corny and no one thinks about stuff that much anymore.</span></p>
<p><strong>It's weird too, because you feel like the trends change by the minute.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah. I feel like as far as trends right now, I'm happy about seeing some harder, darker art again. I've started seeing a lot of people's projects get darker and heavier. Which is good, because that's my favorite type of art.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I feel like recently, I started seeing people like good art again, which gives me hope. Because for a while, I don't think anyone cared.</span></p>
<p><strong>Where do you see the live aspect of your performance, your project, your sound going within the next few months to a year? Are you trying to play certain shows, develop your sound, expand it?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I want to make shows a little bit more theatrical than they are right now. I want to add some different elements and some props and stuff that will make them a little bit more interesting to watch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I would love to, for the release of the EP, maybe get some other instruments and have a little mini-orchestra to really flush out the sound and make the release show special. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, I have a lot of ideas, especially for live performance and visuals, but I feel like the sound, I'm actually really pleased with the sound.</span></p>
<p><strong>That sounds sick. I feel like that's a little underutilized, that theatrical element.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It's hard when I'm playing guitar and singing, because I can't be like a pop diva prancing around the stage when I have a guitar on. I have to be near the mic stand. But I do want to move around and do some more theatrical stuff and have other elements.</span></p>
<p><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>IN CONVERSATION WITH BRANDON TONG</title>
        <author>
            <name>Benji</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://struckmelikeachord.com/in-conversation-with-brandon-tong-2.html"/>
        <id>https://struckmelikeachord.com/in-conversation-with-brandon-tong-2.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/Brandon28-copy.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2025-11-12T20:52:23-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/Brandon28-copy.jpg" alt="" />
                    IN CONVERSATION WITH BRANDON TONG Interview: Benji Wason Photography: Julia Tarantino Brandon&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/Brandon28-copy.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <h1 class="align-center">IN CONVERSATION WITH BRANDON TONG</h1>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/Brandon28-copy-2.jpg" alt="" width="3463" height="2770" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon28-copy-2-xs.jpg 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon28-copy-2-sm.jpg 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon28-copy-2-md.jpg 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon28-copy-2-lg.jpg 1024w"></figure>
<p>Interview: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/benji_wason/">Benji Wason</a></p>
<p>Photography: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/juliatarantino/">Julia Tarantino</a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brandon Tong of Couch Prints is always working on something new. When I give him a call to discuss his upcoming releases and projects, he’s in the middle of working on a song.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Just some lyrics to this melody I wrote,” he says in a tired voice. “It’s very fruitless so far. But you have to accept that sometimes you’re just going to have fruitless hours and that’s okay.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This day-in day-out dedication to the process is something I noticed about Brandon ever since we first met in August 2021. Our bands shared a rehearsal space, and throughout the summer I would bump into Brandon practicing bass alone when his band wasn’t around — not because he wanted to be a great bassist, but because he was committed to serving whatever role was necessary to make his vision of Couch Prints come to life.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Most things you want to do, you can,” he says during our conversation. “You just have to learn and try, you’ll find your way if you really want to. You can at least approximate some of the artists you’re really into — for me that was satisfying enough when I first actually was writing songs.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Struck Me Like A Chord’s latest feature, I join Tong to discuss middle-America nostalgia, themes of violence and boredom on Couch Prints’ 2022 EP </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Waterfall, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">future side-projects and more. Read the full interview below.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/Brandon21.jpg" alt="" width="5092" height="5060" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon21-xs.jpg 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon21-sm.jpg 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon21-md.jpg 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon21-lg.jpg 1024w"></figure>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Tell me about the new Couch Prints EP </strong><strong><i>Waterfall</i></strong><strong>. Where are you coming from, songwriting-wise, with this release?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For better or worse, my mind just always goes to sort of similar concepts. And a big one of those is growing up in the suburbs. I moved around a lot as a kid because my dad was in the Air Force and my parents split up. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s a lot of these very same-y places that were all over the country — strip malls, Chili’s, Cold Stones and Jamba Juices and stuff. Especially when I settled in Colorado, I just spent so much time in these places that at the time seemed kind of sacred and very important. I worked at Jamba Juice for like five years when I was in high school and middle school. I think a lot of people just got this weird attachment to these franchises and I think those years were so formative that all these settings and my time in the suburbs sort of influences everything. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With Couch Prints the newest record traces the story of a drunk driver and their death and their kind of blasé attitude towards it. I think that I definitely felt, as a teenager, just extremely bored. I went to a good school and it’s not like there was anything particularly wrong, but I feel there’s this very real sense of something lacking in contemporary American society. I wouldn’t necessarily say, you know, “we should all be hunter gatherer types,” but I do think like there’s a certain sense of excitement and danger and whatnot missing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Couch Prints record was kind of like working through that boredom that I felt as a kid and that sort of expressed itself in a way of like, doing drugs and putting yourself in more dangerous situations than necessary because it felt like there was not really anything to do.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And that idea kind of came down to: the major violent event in most Americans’ lives is a car crash. It’s something that kind of transcends class lines.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The whole point of the record is examining the American car crash and how it’s just this violent act that is one of the few ways that we feel a real intensity in our life anymore.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Something I’ve admired about you is the kind of drive you have to take up all the different skills and challenges of being a musician. And I remember, from what I understand, you started a lot later than most of the musicians that I know in terms of actually playing and getting into creating music. So, could you tell me a bit about what your relationship was like to music growing up and then when you realized you wanted to actually start making it?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I always really loved music, but again, growing up where I did there was really little creative output, but I always really liked writing poems and little short stories. And I was really into rap and hip hop growing up, so I would write some raps that, you know, will never see the light of day. But I was pretty into just writing. I liked the idea of writing songs, but I didn’t play instruments and it just didn’t seem viable — it just seemed like a humongous mystery. I didn’t know where I would even begin to take words and make them a full song.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think the sort of big renaissance moment was when I went to college. I wanted to do music, but at this point, I knew literally nothing. So I enrolled in the music program in Denver at CU, Denver, and they were like, “yeah, you know, most kids know an instrument or have some background in it, so it will probably take you some time before you can actually even be accepted into the courses in your program.” So I did a semester of General Ed. I was technically in the music program, but wasn’t allowed to take any classes because I didn’t know anything. After a semester I was like, “okay, well, the kids in this program are like jazz guitarists, and  they are just amazing.” They’re actually totally formed musicians and I haven’t even really started. So I switched programs, but the silver lining of it all was that I got put in a dorm with other people that were in the music program. And so my three roommates were all extremely inspiring. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So much of where this all kind of began was in this moment. I moved in with them and they were all pretty big into making dubstep and metal, which were two genres that I had zero interest in at the time. But just living with them — they had a very DIY ethos. I felt like they were always designing their own album art, and they were DJing shows at this place in Denver that’s pretty big for dubstep.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And they all had, you know, tons of copies of Ableton and — it was just seeing that you can just sort of do it. One of them was a really good drummer, but otherwise they were just kind of dudes producing and just writing on their computers. I guess I was 18, and that was when I got Ableton and I started trying to make beats.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/Brandon17.jpg" alt="" width="4972" height="4972" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon17-xs.jpg 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon17-sm.jpg 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon17-md.jpg 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon17-lg.jpg 1024w"></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A few years later when I moved to New York, I had like a few songs and my old bandmate, Jake and I, just kind of started the project. When I moved to New York I was really surprised by how people are accepting of being in creative fields or even just trying to be, even if it’s not in a super professional way. It’s definitely something I take for granted now. If there was a pathway to be a musician in Colorado, it definitely felt like you had to be shooting for the fences. Like you’re trying to make a big pop album that’s going to be very lucrative — there were just a few genres that made sense. To imagine trying to make some of the music that I’ve made since I came here, it would’ve been laughable. It’s just a much better atmosphere to create, and I think that’s like where I’m at now.</span></p>
<p><strong>After you got to New York, when did Couch Prints start to take shape? What were you trying to accomplish when you started to put that together?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I had written a few of the songs while I was still in Colorado and we were just like sending them back and forth to each other. Then I moved to New York and Jake came and stayed with me for a month.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We rented this studio in Greenpoint and I got my rocket fives and my Minilogue and SM-57 and we just started to record some of the songs, but realized we needed a singer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We pretty quickly texted everyone we knew, which was not a long list. Jake had met Jayanna back in Paris and so she came in. Pretty much the first day we worked with her we spent like 12 hours just recording “Tell You”. It just sounded really nice and we were like, “Okay, this is a perfect little fit.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We first put out an EP on SoundCloud that we took down pretty quickly. It was called </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tony Lambo</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It was supposed to be this story of this Coke dealer from Miami who ends up in some really small rural town in Utah and is just kind of going through life — not actually a part of this town and not really feeling of it, but still going through the sort of human experiences like falling in love and trials and tribulations. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was this story I wanted to tell because I think it mirrored how I felt moving to New York. I didn’t really feel of this place, but I was still being human and living through it.</span></p>
<p><strong>Was there an influence musically that inspired the way the sound of the band took shape? Or was it more just what came out of that collaboration and what started to feel right?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have always been really into crystalline ethereal synth textures. Like probably my biggest influence is The Knife album, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Silent Shout</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but also Björk’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vespertine</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, even Beach House. This very cold, icy synthetic sound.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That was the type of music I’d kind of always made. Then when Jake and I started making music together, he was really into guitar. I really didn’t listen to any rock canon for the most part growing up, not even contemporary indie rock — I was not on Mac DeMarco, I never listened to The Strokes growing up — but Jake was really into that, so he turned me onto a ton of bands from that era.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There was The Drums and Alvvays and Men I Trust. Porches was obviously a big influence. There was a lot of indie being made around 2016 that I feel like was super influential at the time.</span></p>
<p><strong>And that was combining with the other influences you’d already been drawing from with your production?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, exactly. A lot of that music felt very bright and sunny. I think it  was just a desire to make that music but with cooler tones.</span></p>
<p><strong>Right. And what was the sort of journey that you started, from your first releases up until now?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We got pretty lucky from the beginning. Our first couple of songs got a lot of blog play and we were on some Spotify playlists. So when we put out our first two songs, we kind of hit the ground running and we got a deal with this imprint of Fat Possum called Luminelle.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And so that happened and we were very excited. But we really only played I think four or five shows at this point. None of us had ever been in a band and I had certainly never played any instrument live. Kind of as things started kicking off, Covid happened and we were bummed like everyone else, but we just finished the collection of songs that we were working on around that period and put them out that summer in 2020. Admittedly it didn’t stream that well, so we were not asked to do our second project with Luminelle.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After that, we still had an album written that we wanted to finish. So we started working on that and then did a tour run to South by Southwest and around the US. That was just to support the EP and now we are in the final stages of releasing that EP — the full thing comes out September 23rd 2022.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That will kind of mark the end of that project chapter, which will be pretty nice to have.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/Brandon27-2.jpg" alt="" width="2341" height="2341" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon27-2-xs.jpg 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon27-2-sm.jpg 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon27-2-md.jpg 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon27-2-lg.jpg 1024w"></figure>
<p><strong>Going off of that, what does the future look like right now? </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, it’s tough. I think there’s something very draining about the release process. What I’ve seen is kind of the indie rock template — promote through blogs, get your press photos done, you do some marketing online. You kind of have to be on social media pretty frequently. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You have like three singles and then you drop a project, and hopefully have a music video attached to it. There’s just a ton of auxiliary stuff that isn’t making music that I think can be fun, but when you’re on this strict timeline it just sort of drags out and gets pretty draining. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think with Couch Prints, I want to take a step back for a little while, maybe keep playing a few shows here and there, but just really rest on that front. Probably going to be a bit of a relaxation hiatus moment and regroup. But as far as personal stuff, there’s a few different things I want to do. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I really want to start a death metal ambient project — something that can be really heavy and sort of cathartic. I found with Couch Prints, while we were working at the set, we ended up gravitating towards heavier and heavier ways of performing the songs and I’ve always just been really interested in mixing electronic with guitar-based music. I love playing live, so that’s a project I’d like to do.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/Brandon06.jpg" alt="" width="4998" height="4997" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon06-xs.jpg 300w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon06-sm.jpg 480w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon06-md.jpg 768w ,https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/8/responsive/Brandon06-lg.jpg 1024w"></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>IN CONVERSATION WITH GOLDER</title>
        <author>
            <name>Benji</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://struckmelikeachord.com/in-conversation-with-golder.html"/>
        <id>https://struckmelikeachord.com/in-conversation-with-golder.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/6/Golder_2.2.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2025-11-12T20:46:29-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/6/Golder_2.2.jpg" alt="" />
                    Interview: Benji Wason Photography: Julia Tarantino Drew Stier, 21, makes computerrock, his&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://struckmelikeachord.com/media/posts/6/Golder_2.2.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Interview: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/benji_wason/">Benji Wason</a></p>
<p>Photography: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/juliatarantino/">Julia Tarantino</a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Drew Stier, 21, makes computerrock, his term for the kaleidoscopic blend of digital noise, frenzied guitar hooks and candy-sweet melodies that he releases under the name Golder. While the components of Stier’s music are as eclectic as they are chaotic, it’s the sheer strength of his songwriting, his ability to take a colorful maelstrom of digital and organic elements and alchemize them into bite-sized, endlessly replayable tracks that leaves the greatest impression on the listener.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I first met Stier in the summer of 2021 at a Junior Varsity “A F$*KING WEEKEND” show in Bushwick, where young musicians and music fans from across the city crowded a strip of sidewalk in Brooklyn’s industrial underbelly, ravenous for the electric atmosphere of a real-world gathering after a year of isolation. As we wrapped up our interview over Zoom, I got the sense that the forward-looking excitement of that summer hadn’t left him. “It’s really an exciting time because I think there’s a void right now for innovative rock bands,” he tells me, “The only ones I hear are out of London, for some reason. But I think New York is up next.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Struck Me Like A Chord’s first feature interview, I join Stier to discuss new old songs, the origins of Golder, finding inspiration in fashion, and much more. Read the full interview below.</span></p>
<p><strong>To start, tell me about the new tracks that just came out. Where did those come from? Where do you see them fitting in with  the whole catalog?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So those tracks </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">(“Please Pull Back” and “Shouldn’t b”, released 2/25/22)</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I actually made before anything I released on Spotify. I made them, I guess a year and a half ago, before I made the EP in early September 2020.</span></p>
<p><strong>Before the </strong><strong><i>Bike</i></strong><strong> EP came out?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, like way before all of that. I made them and I always liked them, they were on  SoundCloud — and I always kind of had it in the back of my mind that I wanted to remix and re-master them and throw them up, and I just saw the opportunity because I pushed back my next album release a bit. I was just like, oh, this is the perfect time to, you know, remix/remaster that whole thing. So Griff </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">(Ashburn, aka (printer friendly))</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> remixed all of the tracks and made them sound way fucking cooler, and then I just re-mastered them. I think they sound much better, and it’s cool to have them out.</span></p>
<p><strong>Going back to older songs sometimes can be a weird thing. Did you get any new perspectives?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, I mean, these two tracks are definitely different, partially because they’re so old, and I was just sort of throwing stuff at the wall. I feel like the drums are really cool. I usually struggle with drums, but for some reason for these two tracks it just came together in a pretty cool way. So I probably will go back and borrow some of those ideas that I was just trying out for those ones. I like the drums especially on “Shouldn’t b”.</span></p>
<p><strong>It’s cool because you can tell some of the Golder-isms are really embodied, and it’s like the songs are really focused on a couple of core good ideas.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They’re really simple, especially compared to the stuff I’ve been working on lately. I was just like, “Oh, what if I made a rock song?” which is not that common for me anymore. But I like them, they’re fun.</span></p>
<p><strong>On that note, going back in time, when did you start getting into music? When did you start getting into songwriting and stuff in particular and what was your initial development like?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think like a lot of people I started with guitar. I remember I was in this after school band thing and we played “Beat It” by Michael Jackson. And then at the end of the whole thing we all got to play at the House of Blues in LA and it was the biggest deal. We were, like, terrible. I could barely play that riff. But it was really fun. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That band thing got me into playing guitar. Then I heard “Float On” by Modest Mouse and I was like, “This is the coolest thing I’ve ever heard!” My dad was a guitarist and I was like “you have to teach me ‘Float On’ by Modest Mouse!” And then I think through that, like in middle school, I would just everyday spend two or three hours after school playing acoustic guitar. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I feel like that’s the pipeline, you hear one cool riff and need to learn it, then you get into playing acoustic, and then writing songs naturally follows. So, I started writing I think when I was like 12.</span></p>
<p><strong>On that stage of development, when after school you just obsess over going to practice guitar, what artists were you super eager to learn from? What type of things were pushing you in the beginning?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was very much during the hipster folk era, and I wanted so badly to be a hipster. And of course, I lived in the suburbs outside of Los Angeles, so all I had really to go off of was that very crass, consumerist, mildly condescending version of a hipster that you see on like a car commercial for a Subaru Impreza or something. But that’s what I wanted to be. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I got this guitar for my 12th birthday, this acoustic. I would just learn Mumford and Sons, One Republic, I got really into the Fleet Foxes and Sufjan Stevens really young. And then that opened the floodgates. I would play a lot of Arcade Fire and in the beginning like Imagine Dragons or all of those artists. Whoever I could hear on the radio that was sort of folk-y and would work on acoustic guitar. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think it was actually a really good era to start playing guitar. Because really simple, four chord folk music was actually very popular and cool. I feel like it’s at the height of its unpopularity right now, but for a beginner guitarist, a song that uses A-Minor, G and C — and that’s what you hear on the radio — that’s a really good thing to have.</span></p>
<p><strong>Did you progress to getting more into electric guitar at some point?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, I was in a jazz band in high school. I maybe tried to start an alt rock band like eight times and it always would fall apart because very few people do unstructured activity where I’m from. Everything is like, if you play soccer, you’re going to practice. You’re not going to go kick a ball around with your friends. If you’re doing music, you do the music program. Because you can’t put a band on your college apps, but you can throw like, awarded jazz band soloist on your college apps. Convincing anybody to do anything other than something you could throw on a resume was nearly impossible. So I sort of got into playing jazz.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve never been the biggest fan of the genre, but I still love a couple records because I just love music so much. But I was actually quite good at jazz guitar. I won a bunch of awards and stuff and that was sort of my main music thing. I was in two smaller combos and two big band jazz bands, it was really fun. And I would take jazz guitar lessons.</span></p>
<p><strong>You must have learned a ton of music theory and stuff that you wouldn’t have otherwise from that.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was great, because I learned a ton of music theory up to the point where I was like 18, and now I don’t have to think about it at all anymore. Which I forget sometimes that other people don’t quite have, just because it was so long ago now for me. Learning all these things, and then forgetting them intellectually, just knowing intuitively—I think that was really good. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I didn’t really pursue jazz further. So I didn’t become like one of those people that’s like “oh, look at this crazy chord…” I kind of got out of the pipeline.</span></p>
<p><strong>At what point did you start to get into recording and producing? Because I feel like one of your strengths, in addition to being a songwriter, is your production.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I would call myself a producer because I had Logic on my laptop, but I was pretty terrible in high school. I think there’s like a level of pretension that you have, if you listen to a lot of indie rock in high school. I was insufferable, and I feel like there’s a couple times where I’d be hanging out with a rapper or whatever and they’d be like, “yeah, let’s cook up.” I’d be like, “yeah, sure, I can make rap music, that’s easy, beat making is nothing!” And then it would be time to make a beat and I’d just be staring at the DAW like “I have no idea what’s going on…”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So I sort of knew how to produce just from like “oh, I know, chords go here, you need a bass guitar…” Just the basic elements. And I knew how to write a song. So it was definitely trial and error. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think it wasn’t really until sophomore year of college, I was in this class with just the most incredible people and it was, you had to bring in something new every week. The teacher said, “oh, this is a songwriting course, don’t produce anything.” So of course I come in with my voice memo of me playing piano and singing, and then everybody else has a fully produced, fully realized track and it was just like “Holy shit…” From then on, I was just like “I need to learn how to produce.” So because I went to Clive Davis (Institute of recorded music) I would just wake up every morning, book out all the studio time that I could in between classes, and then just do that every day. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So it was later than a lot of other people — I was like 19, 20 when I started figuring it out. But I feel like it’s my main thing now. Which is very funny, because I would not have expected that a few years ago.</span></p>
<p><strong>When did singing and lyric writing come into play? Because that can be such a different challenge compared to just playing music.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I wanted to be a novelist growing up. I’ve always been obsessed with words. So I think pretty much as soon as I started playing guitar I was writing songs, just because it’s always been something that I wanted to do. It felt natural, because I always wrote lots of short stories and stuff growing up. Lots of the first three chapters of a novel, because I wanted to be like Christopher Paolini, he wrote like Eragon when he was like 16. So I would always start novels and then not finish them. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So it came pretty naturally. I think the songwriting and the production sort of were separate at first. But the production, I think of it more as arrangement, and the arrangement is to back up the song. I think I’m pretty dated that way. I think of myself more like Phil Spector or one of those producers, where I feel like the song is first and the production is not a beat, but an arrangement built around the melody of the song and the structure of it.</span></p>
<p><strong>Coming from, like you said, the three chords on the acoustic guitar, I can see how your whole mind framework would be built around “What is the core song as its own thing, and how does everything sprout out of that?”</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Definitely. Nowadays, I sort of write and produce at the same time usually. I’ll start with the drum beat, do some bass stuff, do my chords and then I’ll write over that. But it’s very much at the same time, it sort of feels like the same thing as trying out chords and humming out a melody and playing guitar. I feel like it’s a different process than people who are just like, “Yeah, I make a beat. And then I have the beat, and then I sing on top of it,” and it’s this two-step process inside of one thing at the same time.</span></p>
<p><strong>So when did Golder become a thing? What’s the origin behind taking on that title and becoming this project?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was up in Carmel, New York, working with Chris Paraggio </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">(aka Marcyline)</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on his record </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Treegiver</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that he actually just dropped on BandCamp. I didn’t really know what I was doing at all, but Chris was like, “Do you want to produce this project for me?” And then COVID happened so we were at his house for like three months. We just ended up making this record. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chris had recorded and released materials since high school. Everyone I knew I felt like had these artist projects that stretched back years and years and I was like, “I have nothing!” No music on streaming, two songs that were terrible under a different name. I was working with Chris — every night we would work from 8pm to 4am, sometimes until dawn — and I was like, “I need to do this but for myself.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So I was just trying to figure out how this should come together, what it should be. I was making a lot of music, but it was all like vault stuff and it wasn’t that great. I played one show as Drew Stier before that, and I decided I’m just not the type of artist that just goes by his name. So I picked Golder, just because I felt like the vibe was right. And it also has that deliberate ambiguity that I like, where it’s like, “Is it a person? Is it a band? Is it none of these things?” So I went with it because you have no clue as to what it is.</span></p>
<p><strong>And then soon after that, was that when “Please Pull Back” and those couple of songs started to emerge?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That was a few months later. I actually made an entire five song EP that no one has heard. I shattered my collarbone skateboarding down a rural hill — I was pretty much bedridden for three weeks, and I was on a ton of painkillers. So I was like, “This is the time I’m going to make a record!” I had my arm in a sling. I was like, “Can I make an entire album with just my right hand?” So I did, actually. I programmed all the MIDI with my right hand and sang into my iPhone mic and then air dropped it in. And that was, I mean, I think that was the first Golder project, even though I’m pretty sure one of the songs has two streams and they’re all like, not that great. I was just ripping off Beach House songs, because it was the only music I could listen to.</span></p>
<p><strong>So is that unreleased? </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, it’s private on SoundCloud but I sent it to a few of my friends. And then yeah, after that I was working on music over the summer. I got back to New York and then I started really focusing on releasing stuff.</span></p>
<p><strong>Tell me about the Golder album. It’s such a consistent record and I feel like it has a lot of streams of ideas that are consistent throughout, whether it’s the atonal noise breakdowns or the kind of computery ear candy, or even the literary references dropped around. How was that conceptualized and what was that process like recording it?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I definitely go through a pretty long conceptual phase before making stuff. I need to sort of get the idea of it before making it, and I feel like that process I developed with Chris when he was making his record. He goes crazy. He’s like George R. R. Martin or something, constructing entire universes for these songs to live in. For me, I mostly just want a bit of a conceptual idea of what the thing is. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think the idea itself was sort of something that I developed with Griffin, and it was just, like: computerrock. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s a lot of people that use Ableton as a tape recorder, you know, they’ll play stuff in and then record it. And then there’s a lot of people that make music sort of within the DAW — even if you record an external instrument, the point is getting the internal instruments to sort of fit in with the MIDI. I wanted to flip it on its head and say, “what if instead of seeing these roles as separate, the computer itself is controlling the external world?” So I used, other than drums, pretty much no MIDI. And every single element, instrument, all of that stuff was all recorded in, but super heavily warped in Ableton or pitched up or just like random computer processes to make it fit in and be part of this digital world. So, just the idea of the computer controlling me was the idea behind the record. It’s like rock music, but the computer is in charge.</span></p>
<p><strong>I remember, we talked one time about the “Buy u something nice” hook line. And you were telling me that you just played one note on the guitar, and then used Ableton to pitch it around with some effect. Can you talk about that specific example of this whole concept?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, I think that’s a really good example of the whole thing. I just took the guitar, played one note over and over again. And then each note itself I re-pitched in Little Altar Boy. It took me like three hours to get the part down, because I was re-pitching each individual note.</span></p>
<p><strong>Did you have the melody in mind or were you discovering the melody as you were pitching things around?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think I was sort of discovering. I’m trying to remember — I don’t think I played it on guitar first. I think I might have had some idea of it. I know that I didn’t want it to do the same thing twice originally, I thought that was boring. And I tried a lot of other different ways, but it turned out that that was the only one that sounded good so I ended up sticking with it.  I’m very glad I did, because that’s probably my most recognizable instrumental part at this point.</span></p>
<p><strong>Tell me a little bit about the </strong><strong><i>I can put whatever I want here huh</i></strong><strong> (WIW) collective.  </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, so that was something we formed a little bit over a year ago now. And it was sort of just created as shit-posting Instagram, where we could just have a repository to post memes about each other as a joke.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But at the same time, Chris had already pretty much finished his record, Griffin was releasing a lot as Printer Friendly, I was releasing as Golder, and we were all coming together and realizing we were all making projects at the same time. And we were like, “We could probably band together, and instead of being a bunch of different artists all dropping separately, just having something more cohesive would probably be a bit nicer and more beneficial.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve definitely noticed that. I feel like if I do things for myself, something might work out, but generally not really. Like I was trying to get us “fans also like” on Spotify forever and it just wasn’t happening, because “Hard to Breathe” was on indie chill playlists all over. The vast majority of my listeners were just people who heard it on some dream pop playlist. But then after I made the Whatever I Want playlist, immediately Spotify is like, “Oh, we know who you are.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s really important in person too, obviously, and we want to organize a lot more events. We’re all starting to perform a lot more, so that’s going to be a really big shift. But digitally, creating this web to other people who are releasing is so weirdly beneficial — algorithmically and all of these other ways — and it’s been super helpful. </span></p>
<p><strong>Could you tell me about any conceptual ideas for the new album — where you’re going with that and what some of the reference points are?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I wanted to make a psychedelic pop album. I hate throwback, that’s not what I want to be at all, but I think everyone is sort of inevitably looped into the 20 year cycle. So for me it’s a lot of Deerhoof, The Microphones, Broadcast. Those sorts of really colorful indie bands that have this just irrepressible joy to them. I wanted to essentially do that, but more modern sounding and with full use of digital tools. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think it essentially takes everything that was in the last record, and just polarizes it, and then puts it all right next to each other. So when it gets noisy, it gets really noisy. And when it gets pop, I’m doing like the most sugary, candy coated melodies I could think of. Like Britney Spears or some pop act where it’s just the most repetitive little thing that will stick in your head. I wanted to just mash all of these polar extremes together and go back and forth between them. So, that’s sort of the idea behind the album. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I also got this Moog sub-harmonicon, and it makes a lot of really fun noises. So maybe half of the record involves this modular synth doing repetitive patterns, randomness, or some type of squealing, crazy noise. That was sort of how I wanted to include synth looping in the style of a hyper pop or a hyper pop adjacent rap artist without feeling too uncomfortable.</span></p>
<p><strong>I have a couple rapid fire-esque questions just before we wrap things up. Are there any instruments or plugins that you feel are part of your style or habits, and that just feeds into everything you create? </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All of my instruments are from like five things. Essentially I have my Strat, my acoustic, my Sub-Harmonicon and my MicroFreak, a shaker, and then my voice. That’s pretty much every noise. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to plugins, I feel like it’s a two-step process because Griff mixed this record, but he went super hard with the mixing so there’s massive amounts of panning and the album’s constantly moving between left and right, which is fun. I don’t quite know what he did for that. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For me, the Decapitator by SoundToys is my go to distortion. I love the Glue compressor. And probably OTT, on this new record is really important. It’s a multiband compressor. So if you hear in EDM or hyper pop they have these really glowy, crispy high ends, it’s through upward expansion. I feel like people more and more have just been throwing it on everything, because it just makes it sound better. I’ve been using it on vocals a lot to get a more digicore, crispier hyper pop sound.</span></p>
<p><strong>What art or artists, whether it’s musical or any kind of artist, is inspiring you most recently?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was at The Met last night and there was a super sick, I don’t know what to call it but like all of the parts of Black Country New Road that aren’t rock music — it’s organic, minimalist, sort of Steve Reich-y and it always has saxophones in it. I feel like I hear it a lot at museums, these looping saxophone riffs and all these interlocking textures. I went to The Met and me and my girlfriend, we went to the fashion exhibit — she used to work for this designer Yoli who just makes the coolest no-waste clothing — and it just had this really cool looping minimalist music in the background. And then some of the coolest dresses I’ve ever seen. I think increasingly fashion has been a big influence on me.</span></p>
<p><strong>That’s awesome, I’ve got to check that out.</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s on exhibit until September, I highly recommend it. The Met hasn been on their shit. They’ve modernized a lot since the last time I went there. I feel like usually when places are like “We’re appealing to a younger audience!” they just get worse, but The Met — I would totally go right now even if you’ve been many times because it’s in such a different state. </span></p>
<p><strong>Is there a single book, an interview with an artist that you saw or just a general mindset that you would recommend to someone who’s trying to develop as a musician or a songwriter?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I love Camus. So maybe The Myth of Sisyphus. It’s just a really cool book on radical freedom and trying to make sense of the world, and then also free yourself from the bounds that we’re sort of all put in. Just one of those big point-of-life essays. I think it’s a really good thing for every artist to read. I know a lot of people have told me that they got super depressed after reading it, but for me it was really exhilarating — I always feel like it frees you, which is nice.</span></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
